<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    //Beaches-description text for each item
    <string name="beaches_kolovare">One of the most famous beaches in Zadar, Kolovare beach is pebble and rocky beach, partly paved. Nice place to seat and relax.\nLess than 10 min walk from Zadar Bus Station, or from town center. Great for families with kids because there are 2 playing grounds.\nSports equipment for water sports can be rented. Facilities includes cafes, restaurants, public toilets, outdoor showers.</string>
    <string name="beaches_borik">Borik beach is located 4 kilometers from the city centre. It\'s good for kids, as the bay is shallow with a sandy bottom. One part of the beach is sandy and the other gravel.\nThis section is exclusively focused on tourism and the entire section has been rearranged so that there are numerous activities for children such as slides, pools, as well as numerous sports and entertainment facilities.\nThere are plenty of places for refreshments, water-sports, beach games as well as toilets, showers and changing cubicles.</string>
    <string name="beaches_diklo">Heading west from Borik is a beach-lined coastal path studded with places to eat and drink, surrounded by ever more peaceful residential areas and the beach area of Diklo. It’s a quieter place to stay, relax and bathe.</string>
    <string name="beaches_public_pool">Part of Kolovare Beach, a unique place for swimming and water jumping. It contains a swimming pool and a 10m high diving board.</string>
    <string name="beaches_nin_lagoon">Located near the historical town of Nin, around 20 km from Zadar. The lagoon includes several kilometers of sandy beaches.  Suitable for children. </string>
    <string name="beaches_saharun">Located on Long Island (Croatian: \"Dugi otok\"), Saharun beach is one of the most famous beaches in Croatia. Known for its clean and turquoise sea, surrounded by pine trees that provide a welcome shade in the summer. </string>


    //Nightlife-description text for each item
    <string name="nightlife_ledana">Icehouse lounge &amp; bar is a modern designed bar where architects design able to correlate historical value to modern trends and requirements. Former icehouse space that housed the bar was built in the early 19th century as a building for storing ice passed from Velebit, and served for the surrounding urban café for the first ice cream and drinks.
                                    \nThe only such icehouse preserved until today in Croatia. An integral part of the bar has a large terrace which is part of the beautiful gardens of Queen Jelena Madijevke, the first character of a public park in Croatia.
                                    \nThe unique symbiosis that creates an environment in which you can certainly find a place for themselves, whether it’s a beautiful morning, nice day or evening party.\n\nWorking hours: 08:00 a.m. &#8211; 04:00 a.m.  </string>
    <string name="nightlife_yachting">A super, modern bar by the Borik marina, with a great selection of drinks and a terrace with live music. Recommended for easy early evening drinking.\nSail into the cordially named Yachting Bar in case you are feeling peckish. It offers croissants, hot and cold sandwiches, toasts, and all the other snacks one would desire for immediate hunger satisfaction.\n\nWorking hours: 07:00 a.m. &#8211; 05:00 a.m.</string>
    <string name="nightlife_kult">In the very heart of Zadar this café by day and bar by night is a popular spot for students. There are DJ nights, karaoke nights, big screens for sports…\nFun, friendly and lively. Good cocktails too!\n\nWorking hours: 07:00 a.m. &#8211; 01:30 a.m.</string>
    <string name="nightlife_svarog">More of a nightclub than a bar, Svarog is on the stone-flagged Trg pet bunara and is one of the most popular nightspots in Zadar.\nThe music is mainly R’n’B with a smattering of house. Very busy at weekends.\n\nWorking hours: 08:00 p.m. &#8211; 06:00 a.m.</string>
    <string name="nightlife_podroom">Podroom is a night club and place for party goers who wish to live and let live! Though open only on weekends with DJs as hosts, it can receive up to 400 guests and has special booths for a dozen people max… plus a VIP room. So come and join in the action!\n\nWorking hours: 01:00 a.m. &#8211; 06:00 a.m.</string>
    <string name="nightlife_labodega">Conveniently located in the heart of the Old City, this is a great spot for drinking some superb wine. This chic and trendy wine bar at night also offers a breakfast and brunch menu for the early birds to enjoy the sights and sounds of the most popular street, Kalelarga, by day.\n\nWorking hours: 07:00 a.m. &#8211; 01:30 a.m.</string>
    <string name="nightlife_garden">Opened by two members of Brit reggae outfit UB40, this spectacular garden atop the city walls used to be the coolest hangout in the former Yugoslavia.\nNow, coolly minimalist with ultra-comfortable loungers, it\'s a perfect place for enjoying drinks, sunshine, views, a game of chess and hot summer nights to the tune of nu jazz, dub, latin, breaks and downtempo electronica.\n\nWorking hours: 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 01:30 a.m.</string>


    //Cuisine-description text for each item
    <string name="cuisine_lamb">Spit-roasted lamb is one of the most typical and tastiest Dalmatian dishes. The whole lamb is put on a spit and roasted on an open fire of aromatic wood until the skin becomes of golden yellow colour. Before being roasted the meat can be marinated in oil into which aromatic herbs are added.</string>
    <string name="cuisine_dalmatian_plate">Don\'t miss the chance to try the best of Dalmatia. Prossciuto, semi-hard cheese, salted pilchards, olives, small onions, home baked bread.\nNext to domestic red wine, get down to a real Dalmatian brunch. </string>
    <string name="cuisine_octopus">Lovers of seafood will be pleased to find yet another such dish on the list. And what a dish it is! The main ingredients include octopus und potatoes, but the key is the peka.\nThe ingredients, a drop of olive oil and herbs are placed in a cast-iron or earthenware pot where they slowly cook, covered with a lid with hot coals on top of it.\nPeka is prepared in a fireplace and it takes a couple of hours to finish. It’\s a true culinary art, but well worth the wait.</string>
    <string name="cuisine_fish">With the Adriatic sea on your doorstep it would be criminal to leave before trying some fresh fish grilled ‘Dalmatian style’. The method is very basic – wood fire, grill, and some olive oil – but the results are anything other than basic.\nBest served with some garden-grown blitva (chard) and potatoes and washed down with a glass of Plavac Mali. Great Mediterranean dish and healthy to boot.</string>
    <string name="cuisine_risotto">Another dish that is popular in the Dalmatian region is crni rižot, or black risotto. Cuttlefish and squid are the star of this risotto, which is given its unique presentation thanks to ink from the cuttlefish which is added to the dish just before it is finished.\nA bit of grated parmesan cheese and you are ready to go. This is a heavy meal and best washed down with a glass of red wine.</string>
    <string name="cuisine_pasticada">Dalmatinska pašticada, or just pašticada, is a stewed beef dish cooked in a special sauce and served usually with gnocchi or homemade pasta.\nThe long and meticulous preparation, and the range of fascinating ingredients such as roasted bacon, onions, parsley, nutmeg, prunes, and the sweet dessert wine prošek, helps the wonderful flavours come out.</string>
    <string name="cuisine_shrimp">Buzara is a method of cooking seafood, mainly crustaceans and shellfish, wildly used in Dalmatia. Scampi, shrimps, mussels or clams are shortly cooked with white wine, garlic, parsley and breadcrumbs. Tomato paste is sometimes added for color.\nThis is the simplest, yet one of the most delicious ways to prepare shrimps or mussels.\nRoll your sleeves (yes, buzara is eaten with hands), and indulge in this yummy Croatian dish.</string>

</resources>